this next video is on inferring
下一个视频是关于推理的
I like to think of these tasks
我喜欢思考这些任务
where the model takes a text as input and
其中模型将文本作为输入和
perform some kind of analysis
执行某种分析
so this could be
所以这可以是
extracting labels extracting names
提取标签提取名称
kind of understanding the sentiment of a text
理解一篇文章的情感
that kind of thing
诸如此类的事情
so if you want to
所以如果你想
extract a sentiment
提取情感
positive or negative of a piece of text
肯定的或否定的一段文字
in traditional machine learning workflow
在传统的机器学习工作流程中
you'd have to collect the label dataset
你必须收集标签数据集
train the model
训练模型
figure out how to deploy the model somewhere in the
找出如何将模型部署到
cloud and make inferences
猜测并推断
and that can work pretty well but it was
这可以很好地工作，但它是
just a lot of work
只是要做很多工作
to go through that process
来完成这个过程
and also for every toss such as sentiment
也为每一次折腾如情
versus extracting names versus something else
而不是提取名字和其他东西
you have to train
你必须训练
and deploy a separate model
并部署一个单独的模型
one of the really nice things about Lash Language Model
这是鞭笞语言模型的优点之一
is that for many tasks like these
这适用于很多这样的任务吗
you can just
你可以
write a prompt and have it start generating results
编写一个提示符，让它开始生成结果
pretty much right away
几乎是马上
and that gives
这就给出了
tremendous speed in terms of application development
应用程序开发的速度非常快
and you can also just use one model one API
你也可以只用一个模型一个API
to do many different
做很多不同的事情
tiles rather than needing to figure out how to
瓷砖，而不是需要弄清楚如何
train and deploy a lot of different models
训练和部署许多不同的模型
and so with that
就这样
let's jump into the code to see
让我们跳到代码中看看
how you can take advantage of this
如何利用这一点呢
so here's a usual starter code
这是一个常用的启动代码
um just run that
运行一下
and
and
the motivating example I'm going to use is a review
我要用的激励例子是复习
for a lap so
跑了一圈
need a nice lap of the bedroom
我想好好看看卧室
and this one additional storage and so on
这是一个额外的存储空间
so
所以
let me write a prompt
我写一个提示符
to classify the sentiment of this
对这种情绪进行分类
and if I want the system to tell me
如果我想让系统告诉我
what is the sentiment
是什么情绪?
I can just write what is the sentiment
我可以把情绪写下来
of the following
以下内容之一
product review
产品评论
with the usual delimiter or the review text and so on
用通常的分隔符或审查文本等
and let's run that
我们运行一下
and this says the sentiment of the product review is
上面写着产品评论的观点是
positive which is actually seems pretty right
正的，这看起来很对
this lamp isn't perfect
这盏灯不完美
but this customer seems pretty happy
但这位顾客似乎很高兴
it seems you're a great company that cares about the
看来你们是一家关心员工的好公司
customers of products
产品客户
so I think positive
所以我认为这是积极的
sentiment seems like the right answer
情绪似乎是正确的答案
now this prints out the entire sentence
现在打印出整个句子
the sentencement of the project review is positive
项目评审的判决是积极的
if you wanted to give a more concise response
如果你想给出更简洁的回答
to make it easier
为了方便起见
for post processing
用于后期处理
I can take this prompt and add another instruction to
我可以接受这个提示，并添加另一条指令
give you answers
给你答案
a single word either positive or negative
一个单词，可以是肯定的，也可以是否定的
so it just prints out positive like this
所以它就像这样输出正数
which makes it easier
这就简单多了
for a piece of text to take dissolve points and
为一段文字取溶点和
process it and do something with it
处理它，用它做点什么
let's look at another prompt
让我们看看另一个提示符
again instead of using the lab review
而不是使用实验回顾
here I have it
就在这里
identify a list of emotions at the right
在右边列出一系列情绪
of the following reviews
以下评论
expressing include no more than 5 items in this list
表达在此列表中不超过5项
so launch language models are pretty good at extracting
所以发射语言模型很擅长提取
specific things
具体的事情
all of a piece of text in this case we're expressing
在这种情况下，我们要表达的是一段文本
the emotions and this could be useful for understanding
情绪，这可能有助于理解
how your customers
你的客户
think about the particular product
想想具体的产品
for longer customer support
获得更长的客户支持
organizations is important to
组织对于
understand if a particular user is extremely upset
了解某个用户是否非常沮丧
so you might have a
所以你可能有
different classification problem like this
这是不同的分类问题
is the right to the final review expressing anger
终审权是在表达愤怒吗
because if someone is really angry it might
因为如果有人真的很生气的话
merit paying extra attention
额外关注的优点
to have a customer review
进行客户评论
to have customer support or customer success
获得客户支持或客户成功
reach out to figure what's going on and
去弄清楚发生了什么，然后
make things right for the customer
为客户做正确的事情
in this case the customer is not angry
在这种情况下，顾客并没有生气
and notice that
注意到
with supervised learning
通过监督学习
if I had wanted to build all of these
如果我想建造所有这些
classifiers there's no way
分类器没有办法
I would have
我会的
been able to do this with supervised learning in
能够做到这一点与监督学习
just a few minutes that you saw me do so in this video
就在几分钟之前，你们在这个视频中看到了
I encourage you to pause this video and
我鼓励大家暂停视频
try changing some of these prompts
尝试更改其中一些提示
maybe ask if the customer is
也许可以问问顾客是否愿意
expressing delight or ask if
表示高兴或询问的
there are any missing parts
有任何缺失的部分
and see if you can get the prompt to
看看你能不能得到提示
make different inferences about this lap review
对这一圈的回顾做不同的推断
let me show some more
让我再展示一些
things that you can do with this system specifically
你可以用这个系统做的事情
extracting richer information from a customer review
从客户评论中提取更丰富的信息
so information extraction is the part of NLP
所以信息提取是NLP的一部分
of national language processing
民族语言处理
that relates to taking a piece of text
这与取一段文字有关
and extracting certain things that you want to know
提取你想知道的某些东西
from the text
摘自原文
so in this prompt I'm asking it
所以在这个提示中，我问它
identify the following items
确定以下项目
the item purchase and
项目购买和
enable the company that made the item
启用制造该物品的公司
again if you are trying to summarize many reviews
如果你想总结很多评论
from an online shopping ecommerce website
从网上购物电子商务网站
it might be useful for your lash collection reviews
它可能对你的睫毛系列评论有用
to figure out what were the items who made the item
找出制造这个物品的物品是什么
figure out positive and negative sentiment
找出积极和消极的情绪
to track trends about positive or negative sentiment
跟踪积极或消极情绪的趋势
for specific items or for specific
对于特定的项目或特定的
manufacturers
制造商
and in this example I'm going to ask it to format
在这个例子中，我将要求它格式化
your response as adjacent object
你的反应是相邻物体
with item and brand as the keys
以项目和品牌为关键
and so if I do that
如果我这样做
this says the item is a lamp the brand is Luminar
上面写着这是一盏灯，牌子是Luminar
and you can easily load this into Python dictionary
你可以很容易地将它加载到Python字典中
to then do additional processing on this output
然后对这个输出进行额外的处理
in the examples we've gone through
在我们讲过的例子中
you saw how to write a prompt
您看到了如何编写提示符
to recognize the sentiment
识别情感
figure out if someone is angry and also
弄清楚是否有人生气了
extract the item and the brand
提取项目和品牌
one way to extract all of this information
提取所有这些信息的一种方法
would be to use 3 or 4 prompts and co
会使用3个或4个提示和co
get completion you know 3 times or 4 times extract
完成3到4次提取
these different views one at a time
这些不同的观点一次一个
but it turns out you can actually write a single prompt
但实际上你可以写一个提示符
to extract all of this information at the same time
同时提取所有这些信息
so let's say identify the fine items
所以我们说，识别好的物品
extract sentiment
提取的情绪
as reviewer expressing anger
作为评论者表达愤怒
item purchase completely made it
道具购买完全成功了
and then here
然后这里
I'm also
我也
going to tell it to format the anger value as a
告诉它将愤怒值格式化为
brilliant value
辉煌的价值
and let me run that
我来运行一下
and this opens a
这就打开了
JSON
JSON
where sentiment is positive anger
哪里的情绪是积极的愤怒
and did no quotes around faults because it also just
并且没有引号，因为它也只是
operates as a broodier value
作为一个孕育值操作
they extracted the items
他们提取了物品
lamp with additional storage instead of lamp
带有额外存储空间的灯，而不是灯
seems okay
似乎好了
but this way you can extract multiple fields
但是这种方式可以提取多个字段
out of a piece of text
从一段文字中
with just a single prompt
只有一个提示
and as usual please feel free to pause the video
和往常一样，请随意暂停视频
and play with different variations on this yourself
你可以自己尝试不同的变化
or maybe even try
或者尝试一下
tupping in a totally different
在一个完全不同的
review to see if we can still extract these things
复习一下，看看我们是否还能提取这些东西
accurately
准确地
now one of the cool applications of seeing the large
这是观察宏观的一个很酷的应用
language models is
语言模型是
inferring topics
推断的话题
given the long piece of text
给定一长段文本
you know what is this
你知道这是什么
piece of text about what are the topics
关于主题的一段文字
here is a fictitious newspaper article
这是一篇虚构的报纸文章
about how government workers uh feel about the agency
关于政府工作人员对该机构的看法
they work for
他们为
so the recent survey conducted by government
最近政府进行了一项调查
and so on results reviewed in NASA was a
NASA审查的结果是
popular department with high satisfaction rating
受欢迎的部门，满意度高
I am a fan of NASA
我是NASA的粉丝
I love the work they do
我喜欢他们的工作
but this is a fictitious article
但这是一篇虚构的文章
and so given an article like this
给定一篇这样的文章
we can ask it
我们可以问它
with this prompt
有了这个提示符
determine five topics that are being discussed
确定正在讨论的五个主题
in the following text
在下面的文本中
let's make each item one or two words long
让我们把每一项写一到两个单词
for Mary response and a
玛丽的回应和a
comma separated list
逗号分隔列表
and so if we run that you know we get out this article
所以如果我们运行它，你知道我们得到了这篇文章
is about a government survey is about job satisfaction
是关于政府调查的还是关于工作满意度的
is about announcer
是关于播音员的
and so on so overall I think pretty nice
所以总的来说我觉得还不错
extraction
提取
of a list of topics and of course you can also
一个主题列表，当然你也可以
split it so you get a
把它分开，得到一个
Python list with the 5 topics that
Python列表中的5个主题
this article was about
这篇文章是关于
and if you have a collection of articles and
如果你有一些文章和
extract topics
提取主题
you can then also use
你也可以用
a large language model
大型语言模型
to help you index into different topics
帮助您索引到不同的主题
so let me use a slightly different topic list
所以让我用一个稍微不同的主题列表
let's say that
假设
we're a news website or something
我们是新闻网站之类的
and you know
你们知道
these are the topics we try and also the government
这些都是我们和政府尝试的话题
engineering employee satisfaction
工程员工满意度
federal governments and
联邦政府和
let's say you want to figure out
假设你想算出
given a news article
给定一篇新闻文章
which of these topics are covered in that news article
这篇新闻文章涵盖了哪些主题
so here is a prompt that I can use
这是我可以使用的提示符
I'm going to say
我要说
determine whether each item
确定每个项目
the fund list of topics is a topic in the text below
基金主题列表是下面文本中的一个主题
give the answer as a list of 01 for each topic
每个题目给出1个答案
and so
所以
right so this is the same story text us before
这就是之前给我们发的故事
so this thing's a story it is about Nazir
所以这是个关于纳齐尔的故事
it's not about local government
这与地方政府无关
it's not about engineering
这与工程无关
it is about employee satisfaction then it is about
首先是员工满意度，然后是
federal government
联邦政府
so with this
有了这个
in machine learning this is sometimes called a
在机器学习中，这有时被称为
zero shop learning
零车间学习
algorithm because we didn't give it any training data
算法，因为我们没有给它任何训练数据
that was label
这就是标签
so that zero shot
这是零射击
and with just a prompt it was able to determine
只需要一个提示，它就能确定
which of these topics are covered in that news article
这篇新闻文章涵盖了哪些主题
and so if you want to
所以如果你想
generate a news alert
生成新闻警报
say so that process news and you know
所以说，过程新闻，你知道
I really like a lot of the work that NASA does
我真的很喜欢NASA做的很多工作
so if you want to build a system that can take this
所以如果你想建立一个系统来处理这个
you know
你知道
put this information into a dictionary and whenever
把这些信息查到字典里
Nasser News pops out
纳赛尔新闻跳出来了
print alert new NASA story they can use this
他们可以用这个来报道NASA的新故事
to very quickly take any article
快速取任意文章
figure out what topics it is about
弄清楚是关于什么话题的
and if the topic includes NASA
如果主题包括NASA
have it print out alert New NASA story
把NASA的新故事打印出来
oh just one thing I use this topic dictionary down here
哦，只有一件事，我用这个主题词典
this prompt that I use up here isn't very robust
我在这里使用的提示符不是很健壮
if I went to the production system
如果我去生产系统
I would probably have it
我可能会有
I'll put the answer as a
我把答案写成a
adjacent format
相邻的格式
rather than as a list because the output
而不是作为列表，因为输出
of the Lash
鞭笞
English model can be a little bit inconsistent
英国模式可能会有一点不一致
so this is actually a pretty brilliant piece of cone
这实际上是一个非常漂亮的锥体
whether you want when you're done watching this video
看完这个视频后，你想不想
feel free to see if you can figure out how to
请随便看看你能不能想出办法
modify this prompt to have it output
修改此提示符以使其输出
JSON instead of a list like this and then
JSON而不是这样的列表，然后
have a more robust way
有更强大的方法吗
to tell if a bigger article is a story about NASA
来判断一篇更大的文章是否是关于NASA的故事
so that's it for inferring
这就是推断
and in just a few minutes you can build
只需几分钟，你就可以完成
multiple systems for making inferences about text
对文本进行推理的多个系统
that previously does it have
这是之前的情况
taken days or even weeks for a
花几天甚至几周的时间
skilled machine learning developer
熟练的机器学习开发人员
and so I find this very exciting that
所以我觉得这非常令人兴奋
both for skilled machine learning developers
对于熟练的机器学习开发人员来说都是如此
as well as for people that are
对那些人也是一样
newer to machine learning
机器学习的新事物
you can now use prompting to very quickly build and
您现在可以使用提示来非常快速地构建和
start making inferences on pretty complicated
开始做一些非常复杂的推论
natural language processing tasks like these
像这样的自然语言处理任务
in the next video we'll continue to talk about
下个视频我们会继续讨论
exciting things you could do
你可以做一些令人兴奋的事情
with large language models
使用大型语言模型
and we'll go on to
我们将继续
transforming how you take one piece of text
改变你看待一段文字的方式
and transform it into a different piece of text
然后把它转换成另一段文字
such as translated to a different language
比如翻译成另一种语言
let's go on to the next video
我们继续下个视频